Book Without Words is a action film directed by Chan Lit-ban.
Book Without Words is a 1965 Cantonese martial arts film
directed by Chan Lit-Ban and starring Cheung Ching.
Kot Siu Kwun, played by Cheung Ching.
Blue Wolf, played by Sek Kin.
Blue Wolf, played by Suet Nei.
Purple Wolf, played by Connie Chan Po-Chu.
White Wolf, played by Kenneth Tsang.
Red Wolf, played by Nancy Sit Ka-Yin.
Doctor Zhivago () is a 1965 epic historical romance film directed by David Lean with a
screenplay by Robert Bolt, based on the 1957 novel by Boris Pasternak.
The story is set in Russia during World War I and the Russian Civil War.
The film stars Omar Sharif in the title role as Yuri Zhivago, a married physician and poet whose life is altered
by the Russian Revolution and subsequent civil war, and Julie Christie as his lover Lara Antipova.
Geraldine Chaplin, Tom Courtenay, Rod Steiger, Alec Guinness, Ralph
Richardson, Siobhán McKenna, and Rita Tushingham play supporting roles.
Although immensely popular in the West, Pasternak's book
was banned in the Soviet Union for decades.
As the film could not be made there, it was instead filmed mostly in Spain.
It was an international co-production between
Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer and Italian producer Carlo Ponti.
Contemporary critics were critical of its length at over three hours and claimed that it trivialized history,
but acknowledged the intensity of the love story and the film's treatment of human themes.
At the 38th Academy Awards, Doctor Zhivago was nominated for ten Oscars (including Best Picture) and won five:
Best Adapted Screenplay, Original Score, Cinematography, Art Direction, and Costume Design.
It also won five awards at the 23rd Golden Globe
Awards including Best Motion Picture.
As of 2022, it is the ninth highest-grossing film
worldwide after adjusting for inflation.
In 1998, it was ranked 39th by the American Film Institute on their 100 Years...
100 Movies list, and by the British Film Institute in 1999
as the 27th greatest British film ever.